# Jeongwhan Choi

jeongwhan.choi@yonsei.ac.kr Homepage Link Google Scholar Link

#### Introduction

I am currently a Ph.D. student at Yonsei University. I relocated to KAIST in February 2024 to continue my research with my advisor, Prof. Noseong Park, and currently I am staying at KAIST. My research interests span a variety of areas, including graph neural networks, recommender systems, spatio-temporal forecasting, and differential equations. I have developed graph-based deep learning methods inspired by differential equations in natural science, such as heat diffusion and reaction-diffusion equations. Recently, my focus on research has been extending the self-attention mechanism, the heart of Transformers, into the concept of graph signal processing.

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

- Artificial Intelligence
  - Graph Neural Networks
  - Recommendation (Collaborative Filtering and Sequential Recommendation)
  - Spatiotemporal Forecasting
  - Differential Equation-based Deep Learning
  - Transformers
- Software Engineering
  - Software Defect Prediction
  - AI-based Software Analytics

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Integrated Ph.D. Student

Aug 2020 - Now

Big Data Analytics Laboratory (BigDyL), Yonsei University (Advisor: Prof. Noseong Park)

Undergraduate Student Research Assistant

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

AI & SE Lab, Jeonbuk National University (Advisor: Prof. Duksan Ryu)

Undergraduate Student Research Assistant

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

Software System and Engineering Laboratory (SSEL), Jeonbuk National University (Advisor: Prof. Suntae Kim)

# EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

### Integrated Ph.D., Artificial Intelligence

Sep 2020 - Now

Yonsei University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

## Bachelor, Software Engineering

Mar 2016 - Aug 2020

Jeonbuk National University, Jeonju, Jeollabuk Do, Republic of Korea

• magna cum laude (GPA: 3.98/4.50)

## Publication

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Sumin Park, Hyowon Wi, Sung-Bae Cho, and Noseong Park, "PANDA: Expanded Width-Aware Message Passing Beyond Rewiring", in International Conference on Machine Learning (*ICML*), 2024.

Jayoung Kim, Yehjin Shin, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Hyowon Wi, Noseong Park, "Polynomial-based Self-Attention for Table Representation Learning", in International Conference on Machine Learning (*ICML*), 2024. [arXiv]

Seoyoung Hong, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Yeon-Chang Lee, Srijan Kumar, Noseong Park, "SVD-AE: Simple Autoencoders for Collaborative Filtering", in International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (*IJCAI*), 2024. [arXiv]

Youn-Yeol Yu, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Woojin Cho, Kookjin Lee, Nayong Kim, Kiseok Chang, ChangSeung Woo, Ilho Kim, SeokWoo Lee, Joon Young Yang, Sooyoung Yoon, and Noseong Park, "Learning Flexible Body Collision Dynamics with Hierarchical Contact Mesh Transformer", in *ICLR*, 2024. [arXiv]

**Jeongwhan Choi\***, Hyowon Wi\*, Chaejeong Lee, Sung-Bae Cho, Dongha Lee, Noseong Park, "RDGCL: Reaction-Diffusion Graph Contrastive Learning for Recommendation", arXiv preprint arXiv: Arxiv-2312.16563, 2023. [arXiv]

Yehjin Shin\*, **Jeongwhan Choi**\*, Hyowon Wi, Noseong Park, "An Attentive Inductive Bias for Sequential Recommendation beyond the Self-Attention", in AAAI, 2024. [Acceptance Rate 23.75% (2342/12100)] [arXiv]

**Jeongwhan Choi\***, Hyowon Wi\*, Jayoung Kim, Yehjin Shin, Kookjin Lee, Nathaniel Trask, Noseong Park, "Graph Convolutions Enrich the Self-Attention in Transformers!", arXiv preprint arXiv: Arxiv-2312.04234, 2023. [arXiv]

Yeon Uk Jeong, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Noseong Park, Jae Yong Ryu, and Yi Rang Kim, "Predicting Drug-Drug Interactions: A Deep Learning Approach with GCN-Based Collaborative Filtering", *Available at SSRN 4640046* 2023.

Seonkyu Lim, Jaehyeon Park, Seojin Kim, Hyowon Wi, Haksoo Lim, Jinsung Jeon, **Jeongwhan Choi**, and Noseong Park, "Long-term Time Series Forecasting based on Decomposition and Neural Ordinary Differential Equations", In *IEEE International Conference on Big Data* (*Big Data*), 2023.

Jaehoon Lee, Chan Kim, Gyumin Lee, Haksoo Lim, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Kookjin Lee, Dongeun Lee, Sanghyun Hong and Noseong Park, "HyperNetwork Approximating Future Parameters for Time Series Forecasting under Temporal Drifts", *NeurIPS 2023 Workshop on Distribution Shifts* (*DistShift*), 2023.

**Jeongwhan Choi** and Duksan Ryu, "QoS-Aware Graph Contrastive Learning for Web Service Recommendation", In *Proceedings of the 30th Asia-Pacific Software Engineering Conference (APSEC 2023*), 2023.

**Jeongwhan Choi** and Noseong Park, "Graph Neural Rough Differential Equations for Traffic Forecasting", *ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST)*, 2023. [paper][IF=10.489]

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Seoyoung Hong, Noseong Park and Sung-Bae Cho, "GREAD: Graph Reaction-Diffusion Networks", In *Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)*, 2023. [paper][code][Paper Acceptance rate: 27.94% (1.827/6.538)]

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Seoyoung Hong, Noseong Park and Sung-Bae Cho, "Blurring-Sharpening Process Models for Collaborative Filtering", In *Proceedings of the 46th ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)*, 2023. [paper][code][Paper Acceptance rate: 20.1% (165/822)]

**Jeongwhan Choi** and Duksan Ryu, "Graph Convolution-based Collaborative Filtering for Web Service QoS Ranking", In *Proceedings of the 25th Korea Conference on Software Engineering (KCSE 2023*), 2023, pp. 58-67.

Hwangyong Choi, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jeehyun Hwang, Kookjin Lee, Dongeun Lee and Noseong Park, "Climate Modeling with Neural Advection-Diffusion Equation", *Knowledge and Information Systems*, Jan. 2023. [paper] [IF=3.205(2021) Five year impact factor]

Jaehoon Lee, Chan Kim, Gyumin Lee, Haksoo Lim, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Kookjin Lee, Dongeun Lee, Sanghyun Hong and Noseong Park, "Time Series Forecasting with Hypernetworks Generating Parameters in Advance", arXiv preprint arXiv: Arxiv-2211.12034, 2022. [paper]

Seoyoung Hong, Heejoo Shin, **Jeongwhan Choi**, and Noseong Park, "Prediction-based One-shot Dynamic Parking Pricing", In *Proceedings of the 31st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM*), 2022.[paper][code]

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Hwangyong Choi, Jeehyun Hwang and Noseong Park, "Graph Neural Controlled Differential Equations for Traffic Forecasting", In *AAAI*, 2022. [paper][code][Regular Paper Acceptance rate: 14.2% (1,161/8,198)] [Overall Acceptance rate: 15.2% (1,370/9,020)]

Taeyong Kong, Taeri Kim, Jinsung Jeon, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Yeon-Chang Lee, Noseong Park and Sang-Wook Kim, "Linear, or Non-Linear, That is the Question!", In *Proceedings of the 15th ACM International Web Search and Data Mining Conference* (WSDM), 2022. [paper][code] [Regular Paper Acceptance rate: 15.8% (80/505)] [Overall Acceptance Rate: 18% (315/1,765)]

**Jeongwhan Choi** and Duksan Ryu, "Self-Supervised Learning Using Feature Subsets of Software Defect Data", In *Proceedings of the Korea Software Congress* (KSC), Dec. 2021, pp.203-205.

Jeehyun Hwang, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Hwangyong Choi, Kookjin Lee, Dongeun Lee and Noseong Park, "Climate Modeling with Neural Diffusion Equations", In *Proceedings of the 21st IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)*, 2021. [paper] [code] [Regular paper acceptance rate: 9.9% (98/990)] [Overall Acceptance Rate: 20% (198/990)]

**Jeongwhan Choi** and Duksan Ryu, "Bayesian Optimization Framework for Improved Cross-Version Defect Prediction", *KIPS Transactions on Software and Data Engineering (KTSDE)*, Vol. 10, No. 9, pp. 339-348, Sep. 2021.

Jeongwhan Choi, Jinsung Jeon, and Noseong Park, "LT-OCF: Learnable-Time ODE-based Collaborative Filtering", In *Proceedings of the 30th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM)*, 2021. [paper] [code] [Regular paper acceptance rate: 21.7% (271/1,251)] [Overall Acceptance rate: 22% (1,101/4,989)]

Jeongwhan Choi and Duksan Ryu, "Bayesian Optimization Framework for Cross-Version Defect Prediction", In *Proceedings of the 23rd Korea Conference on Software Engineering (KCSE 2021)*, 2021, pp. 63-72. [Best Paper]

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Jiwon Choi, Duksan Ryu and Suntae Kim, "Improved Prediction for Configuration Bug Report Using Text Mining and Dimensionality Reduction", *Journal of KIISE*, 2021, Vol. 48, No. 1, pp. 35-42.

**Jeongwhan Choi** and Duksan Ryu, "A Study on the Applicability of Transfer Learning Techniques for Cross-Project Defect Regression", In *Proceedings of the Korea Software Congress* (KSC), 2020, pp. 150 - 152.

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Duksan Ryu, and Suntae Kim, "Comparative Study of Transfer Learning Models for Cross-Project Automotive Software Defect Prediction", In *Proceedings of the Korea Computer Congress* (KCC), 2020, pp. 257–259.

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Jiwon Choi, Duksan Ryu, and Suntae Kim, "Prediction for Configuration Bug Report Using Text Mining", In *Proceedings of the 22nd Korea Conference on Software Engineering (KCSE 2020)*, 2020, pp. 350–357.

**Jeongwhan Choi**, Jiwoo Noh, and Suntae Kim, "Prediction Techniques for Difficulty Level of Hanja Using Multiple Linear Regression", *J. Inst. Internet, Broadcast. Commun.*, vol. 19, no. 6, 2019.

Seounghan Song, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Mingu Kang, and Cheoljung Yoo, "A Software Module That Analyzes the Relationship Between Headline and Content of the Web Article: CHIMERA", in *Proceedings of the 2019 KHIT DCS Summer Conference*, 2019, vol. 14, pp. 437–440.

**Jeongwhan Choi**, "Iceberg-Ship Classification in SAR Images Using Convolutional Neural Network with Transfer Learning", *J. Internet Comput. Serv.*, vol. 19, no. 4, pp. 35–44, 2018.

Excellent Paper Award, Yonsei University (Best paper in Dept. of Artificial Intelligence)	Jan 2024
Innovation Award, Yonsei University (Best paper in Dept. of Artificial Intelligence) [link]	Jul 2022
Best Paper Awards in the $23\mathrm{rd}$ Korea Conference on Software Engineering (KCSE $2021$ )	Feb 2021
Best Paper Awards in Dep. of Software Engineering	Dec 2019
Best Paper Awards, Korean Institute of Information Technology	Jun 2019
The National Scholarship for Science and Engineering, KOSAF(Korea Student Aid Foundation)	2018-2019

• This scholarship supports undergraduates with strong academic performance in science and engineering, with the purpose of developing future leaders in those fields.

Academic Excellent Scholarship

2016-2019

#### Talks

Invited talk on Top-conference session, Korea Software Congress (KSC 2023)	$Dec\ 2023$
Talk on 1st Seminar held by Graph User Group (GUG)	Jun~2023
Invited talk on Top-conference session, Korea Computer Congress (KCC 2023) [slides]	Jun~2023
Talk on 2023 KSIAM AI Winter School, held by Korean Society for Industrial and Applied Mathem (KSIAM)[slides][website]	natics Feb 2023
Talk on 1st Workshop on AI held by Yonsei Univ. [slides][poster]	Oct 2022
Poster presentation for AIGS Symposium 2022 held at the COEX Grand Ballroom [poster]	Aug~2022
Invited talk on Top-conference session, Korea Computer Congress (KCC 2022) [slides]	Jul~2022
Tutorial on Korea Artificial Intelligence Association (KAIA)	Nov 2021

- Topic: "Graph-based Collaborative Filtering and Neural ODEs"
- This talk is part of a tutorial called "Deep Learning Inspired by Differential Equation" [slides].

### SERVICE

- Reviewer in IEEE Transactions on Image Processing 2024
- Reviewer in KDD 2024
- Reviewer in IJCAI 2024
- Reviewer in Journal of Intelligent & Fuzzy Systems 2024
- Reviewer in IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering 2024
- Program Committee in IRonGraphs 2024: First International Workshop on Graph-Based Approaches in Information Retrieval, co-located with ECIR 2024
- Reviewer in 4th Workshop on Graphs and More Complex Structures for Learning and Reasoning (GCLR) colocated with AAAI 2024
- Reviewer in SDM 2024
- Reviewer in AAAI 2023
- Reviewer in Applied Artificial Intelligence
- Reviewer in KDD 2023
- Reviewer in Learning on Graph Conference (LoG) 2022, 2023
- Reviewer in IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems
- Reviewer in ICDM 2021, 2022

# PATENT AND S/W PROGRAM

[Issued Patent] Apparatus and Method for Processing Spatiotemporal Data Based on Graph Neural Controlled Differential Equations, Noseong Park, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jeehyun Hwang, Hwangyong Choi, U.S.A. Patent(Issued Number: 18/085,109). 2022.12.20

Dec 2022

[Issued Patent] Apparatus and Method for Processing Spatiotemporal Data Based on Graph Neural Controlled Differential Equations, Noseong Park, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jeehyun Hwang, Hwangyong Choi, Domestic Patent(Issued Number: 10-2022-0151819). 2022.11.14

Nov 2022

[S/W] LT-OCF: Learnable-Time ODE-based Collaborative Filtering, Korea Copyright Commission, C-2021-052779, 2021.12.

Dec 2021

[Issued Patent] Apparatus and Method for Collaborative Filtering Based on Learnable-Time Ordinary Differential Equation, Noseong Park, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jinsung Jeon, Japan Patent(Issued Number: 2021-215162). 2021.12.28

Dec 2021

[Issued Patent] Apparatus and Method for Collaborative Filtering Based on Learnable-Time Ordinary Differential Equation, Noseong Park, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jinsung Jeon, U.S.A. Patent(Issued Number: 17/563,726). 2021.12.28

Dec 2021

[Issued Patent] Apparatus and Method for Collaborative Filtering Based on Learnable-Time Ordinary Differential Equation, Noseong Park, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jinsung Jeon, Domestic Patent(Issued Number: 10-2021-0177928). 2021.12.13

\*\*Dec 2021

[Granted Patent] Apparatus and Method for Measuring Difficulty Level of Chinese Character Using Regression Analysis, Suntae Kim, **Jeongwhan Choi**, Jiwoo Noh, Domestic Patent(Application Number:10-2019-0141339). 2019.11. [link]

#### CERTIFICATIONS

### University Machine Learning Camp in Jeju, Jeju University

Aug 2020

• See credential

### IBM Blockchain Foundation for Developers, Coursera

Feb 2018 - Present

• License 5MMQUBFWE2K3 (See credential)

# Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree, Udacity

Jan 2018 - Present

• See credential

## Machine Learning, Coursera

 $July\ 2017$  - Present

• License EEYYGQPCFLN7 (See credential)

# SKILLS

## Tools & Technologies,

- PyTorch, TensorFlow, Python
- Java, C/C++, R, LaTeX, VBA, Unified Modeling Language
- Android, Matlab, Git, RSA
- MySQL, Tomcat, JSP, HTML, Javascript, JUnit

## Skills & Knowledge,

- Artificial Intelligence, Graph Neural Networks, Neural Ordinary Differential Equations (Neural ODEs), Recommender Systems, Transformers, Time-series Forecasting, Spatio-temporal Forecasting, Software Defect Prediction
- Software Engineering, Object Oriented Programming, Design Pattern, Compiler, Software Testing (Static Analysis)
- Text Mining, Image Processing for SAR Image
- ARM Cortex-M3, ESP-8266

The list below includes projects conducted in class, personal projects, and projects conducted during undergraduate research internships. These are all projects I worked on as an undergraduate student.

Prediction for Configuration Bug Report Using Text Mining

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

• The purpose of this project is to predict the configuration bug reports using machine learning techniques and NLP.

Development of capability assessment evaluation algorithm for personalized self-study with Hanja-Chinese parallel  $Dec\ 2018\ -\ Expected\ Nov\ 2019$ 

- The purpose of this project is to solve the problems of existing Hanja character difficulty selection method.
- It includes the technique for measuring the difficulty of Hanja characters using artificial intelligence.
- It also covers personalized learning induction technique using a clustering model.

Stock Price Prediction Model Based LSTM to Maximize Return on Investment

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- The purpose of this project is to predict the long-term stock flow based on the AI prediction model and to derive meaningful ROI.
- This project has a paper which is not submitted.
- See project

Advanced Lane Finding Project

Jul 2018

- The goal is to find the lane line using advanced image processing techniques.
- See project

Vehicle Detection Jul 2018

- The software pipeline using computer vision algorithms to detect vehicles in videos.
- See project

Clone Driving Behavior

Jun 2018

- The goal is to clone driving behavior via the CNN model.
- See project

Recipe Assistant App

Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

- The recipe assistant app which helps people to cook an easy way. This app was implemented by Android and improved by several design patterns.
- See project

Tic-Tac-Toe game for LPC 1768

Jun 2018

- This project is the Tic-Tac-Toe Game using ARM Cortex-M3(LPC 1768)
- See project

Lane Finding Project

Mar 2018

- The goal is to find the lane lines on the road.
- See project

Iceberg Classifier

Jan 2018

• The goal is to create an image classification model that finds icebergs among SAR images collected by satellites. This project has a paper published in JICS.

• See project

Helicopter Battle Game

Apr 2017 - Jul 2017

- This Java project includes the software engineering knowledges such as objective-oriented design, design patterns and so on.
- See project

Smart Mailbox Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

- The smart mailbox project played a role in helping people who forget offline mails through notifications to mobile phones.
- See project